RG 016, Department of Public Health
Connecticut State Library
- Series 30. Local Health Administration, 1931-1981; 12.5 cubic feet
  - Annual Reports of Town Health Officials, 1931-1981; 1996-011; 11.5 cubic feet
    - Prospect, 1931-1970 (Box 16)
    - Putnam, 1931-1974 (Box 16)
    - Redding, 1931-1971 (Box 16)
    - Ridgefield, 1931-1969 (Box 16)
    - Rocky Hill, 1931-1968 (Box 16)
    - Roxbury, 1933-1979 (Box 16)
    - Salem, 1931-1977 (Box 16)
    - Salem, 1931-1977 (Box 16)
    - Salisbury, 1939-1975 (Box 16)
    - Scotland, 1934-1971 (Box 16)
    - Seymour, 1938-1973 (Box 16)
    - Sharon, 1931-1979 (Box 17)
    - Shelton, 1932-1973 (Box 17)
    - Sherman, 1931-1960 (Box 17)
    - Simsbury, 1932-1979 (Box 17)
    - Somers, 1931-1977 (Box 17)
    - Southbury, 1931-1979 (Box 17)
    - Southington, 1931-1981 (Box 17)
    - South Windsor, 1932-1964 (Box 18)
    - Sprague, 1932-1975 (Box 18)
    - Stafford, 1931-1979 (Box 18)
    - Stamford, 1931-1977 (Box 18)
    - Sterling, 1931-1974 (Box 18)
    - Stonington, 1931-1974 (Box 18)
    - Stratford, 1931-1979 (Box 18)
    - Suffield, 1932-1979 (Box 19)
    - Thomaston, 1931-1971 (Box 19)
    - Thompson, 1931-1974 (Box 19)
    - Tolland, 1931-1979 (Box 19)
    - Torrington, 1937-1966 (Box 19)
    - Trumbull, 1931-1979 (Box 19)
    - Union, 1932-1958 (Box 19)
    - Vernon, 1931-1979 (Box 19)
    - Voluntown, 1931-1979 (Box 20)
    - Wallingford, 1936-1979 (Box 20)
    - Warren, 1932-1942 (Box 20)
    - Washington, 1934-1952 (Box 20)
    - Waterbury, 1931-1978 (Box 20)
    - Waterford, 1933-1979 (Box 20)
    - Watertown, 1931-1974 (Box 20)
    - West Hartford, 1932-1978 (Box 21)
    - West Haven, 1931-1977 (Box 21)
    - Westbrook, 1931-1973 (Box 21)
    - Weston, 1934-1977 (Box 21)
    - Westport, 1933-1977 (Box 21)
      See also Aspetuck Valley Health District
    - Wethersfield, 1931-1979 (Box 21)
    - Willington, 1931-1979 (Box 22)
    - Wilton, 1931-1974 (Box 22)
    - Winchester, 1932-1979 (Box 22)
    - Windsor, 1931-1976 (Box 22)
    - Windsor Locks, 1931-1968 (Box 22)
    - Wolcott, 1933-1974 (Box 22)
    - Woodbridge, 1931-1979 (Box 22)
    - Woodbury, 1931-1979 (Box 23)
    - Woodstock, 1931-1974 (Box 23)
    - Aspetuck Valley Health District, 1967-1981 (Box 23)
    - Chesprocott Health District, 1978 (Box 23)
    - East Shore District, 1975-1979 (Box 23)
    - Farmington Valley Health District, 1977-1979 (Box 23)
    - Lower Naugatuck Valley, 1973-1979 (Box 23)
    - Northeast District Department of Health, 1977-1979 (Box 23)
    - Quinnipiack Health District, 1979 (Box 23)
    - Torrington Area Health District, 1970-1973 (Box 23)
    - Laws for functions in Division of Local Health Administration (Box 23)
- Series 31. Not in use.
- Series 32. Tumor Registry Division
  - Case files
    RESTRICTED
    Access to these records is available only to researchers who apply through the department's Human Investigation Committee.
    - 1992-052, 91 cubic feet
    - 1993-130, 201 cubic feet
    - 1995-073, 99 cubic feet
    - 1995-074, 350 cubic feet
- Series 33. Public Health Office Maternal and Child Health Program, 1955-1984; 1995-002; 1 cubic foot
  - Original Young Parent Program State Plan, 1955 (Box 1)
  - AAP - Committee on Adolescents (Box 1)
  - Abortion Information (Box 1)
  - Adolescent Pregnancy Task Force (Box 1)
  - ACOG and AAP Position Statements (Box 1)
  - Venereal Disease Law Re: Minors (Box 1)
  - Medical Social Work and Consultation (Box 1)
  - "Serving School Age Mothers", 1973 January (Box 1)
  - Young Parents Program - Five Year Plan (Box 1)
  - Maternal and Child Health Section, Young Mother's Program, Program and Procedural Manual, 1971 May; 2 copies (Box 1)
  - Connecticut Young Parents Program, MCH Title V - Fund RB, 1979 July 1-1980 June 30; 2 copies (Box 1)
  - Connecticut Young Parents Program, MCH Title V - Fund RB, 1980 July 1-1981 June 30 (Box 1)
  - Connecticut Young Parents Program, MCH Title V - Fund RB, 1979 July 1-1980 June 30 (Box 1)
  - Connecticut Young Parents Program, MCH Title V - Fund RB, 1978 July 1-1979 June 30 (Box 1)
  - Connecticut Young Parents Program, MCH Title V - Fund RB, 1977 July 1-1978 June 30; 2 copies (Box 1)
  - Young Parents Program Progress Report, 1979 (Box 1)
  - Young Parents Program Progress Report, 1978; 3 folders (Box 1)
  - Young Parents Program Progress Report, 1977 (Box 1)
  - Young Parents Program - Contracts Fiscal, 1977 (Box 1)
  - Comprehensive Adolescent Health Care Project, 1984 (Box 1)
- Series 34. Bureau of Laboratories / Laboratory Division, 1943-1976; 2.25 cubic feet
  - 1994-009A
    - Annual Reports, 1943-1956; 14 volumes
      Separate narrative summaries for each division.
      Arranged chronologically by fiscal years. Examination data tabulated by calendar year.
      - 1943/1944 - 1949/1950 (Box 1)
      - 1950/1951 - 1955/1956 (Box 2)
  - T003189
    - Proposal for building addition, 1976 November (Volume Envelope)
- Series 35. Hearing Office, 1893-2014
  - 1994-020, 2 cubic feet
    See also Accessions 2008-039 and 2011-131.
    - Board of Examiners for Nursing minutes, 1905-1992
      - 1905 July-1922 June (Box 1)
      - 1923 January-1939 June (Box 1)
      - 1939 September-1945 June (Box 1)
      - 1945 July-1952 May (Box 1)
      - 1953 January-1960 November (Box 1)
      - 1961 January-1968 April (Box 1)
      - 1968 June-1973 February (Box 1)
      - 1973 April-1976 October (Box 1)
      - 1976 November-1980 July (Box 1)
      - 1980 August-1984 January (Box 2)
      - 1981 January-1987 February (Box 2)
      - 1987 February-1990 April (Box 2)
      - 1990 May-1992 December (Box 3)
    - Board of Examiners for Nursing disciplinary folders, 1939-1960 (Box 3)
  - 2000-004, 8 cubic feet
    - Connecticut Medical Examining Board minutes, 1940-1975 (Box 1)
      - 1940 March-1947 January, 1 volume (Box 1)
      - 1947 January-1949 July, 1 volume (Box 1)
      - 1949 July-1952 November, 1 volume (Box 1)
      - 1952 November-1956 July, 1 volume (Box 1)
      - 1956 July-1961 June, 1 volume (Box 1)
      - 1961 June-1966 March, 1 volume (Box 1)
      - 1966 March-1970 August, 1 volume (Box 1)
      - 1970 October-1975 March, 1 volume (Box 1)
    - Healing Arts minutes, 1944-1975 (Box 1)
      - 1944 July-1961 October, 1 volume (Box 1)
      - 1962 February -1975 October, 1 volume (Box 1)
    - Connecticut State Dental Commission minutes, 1965-1991 (Box 2)
      - 1965 January-1968 June, 1 volume (Box 2)
      - 1968 July-1979 December, 1 volume (Box 2)
      - 1977 July-1978 August, 1 volume (Box 2)
      - 1978 September-1979 December, 1 volume (Box 2)
      - 1980 January-December, 1 volume (Box 2)
      - 1981 January-1982 November, 1 volume (Box 2)
      - 1983 January-1984 December, 1 volume (Box 2)
      - 1985 January-1987 June, 1 volume (Box 2)
      - 1987 September-1991 March, 1 volume (Box 2)
    - Connecticut Homeopathic Medical Examining Board minutes, 1978 November-1989 March; 1 volume (Box 3)
    - Connecticut Board of Examiners for Opticians minutes, 1935-1983; 1 volume (Box 3)
      - 1935 July-1941 July, 1 volume (Box 3)
      - 1941 July-1947 April, 1 volume (Box 3)
      - 1947 Julyt-1956 June, 1 volume (Box 3)
      - 1956 July-1968 June, 1 volume (Box 3)
      - 1968 July-1972 November, 1 volume (Box 3)
      - 1972 November-1975 May, 1 volume (Box 3)
      - 1975 June-1983 November, 1 volume (Box 3)
    - Connecticut State Dental Commission minutes, 1893-1975 (Box 4)
      - 1893-1901, 1 volume (Box 4)
      - 1901 July-1924 June, 1 volume (Box 4)
      - 1924 July-1934 June, 1 volume (Box 4)
      - 1834 July-1944 June, 1 volume (Box 4)
      - 1944 July-1953 June, 1 volume (Box 4)
      - 1953 July-1961 June, 1 volume (Box 4)
      - 1961 July-1964 December, 1 volume (Box 4)
      - 1971 January-1973 December, 1 volume (Box 4)
      - 1974 January-1975 December, 1 volume (Box 4)
      - 1976 July-1977 June, 1 volume (Box 4)
    - Connecticut State Board of Examiners for Physical Therapists minutes, 1941 July-1979 July; 1 volume (Box 5)
    - Connecticut Board of Examiners for Optometrists minutes, 1932-1979; 1 volume (Box 5)
      - 1932 January-1957 October, 1 volume (Box 5)
      - 1957 October-1967 June, 1 volume (Box 5)
      - 1967 October-1974 November, 1 volume (Box 5)
      - 1974 December-1976 December, 1 volume (Box 5)
      - 1977 January-1978 November, 1 volume (Box 5)
      - 1979 January-December, 1 volume (Box 5)
    - Connecticut Board of Veterinary Medicine minutes, 1960 July-1981 March; 1 volume (Box 5)
    - Connecticut Board of Examiners of Embalmers & Funeral Directors minutes, 1963 April-1982 February; 1 volume (Box 5)
    - Connecticut Osteopathic Examining Board minutes, 1911 September-1967 November; 1 volume (Box 5)
    - Connecticut State Barber Board minutes, 1949-1980 (Box 6)
      - 1949 July-1950 June, 1 volume (Box 6)
      - 1955 July-1956 June, 1 volume (Box 6)
      - 1960 July-1961 June, 1 volume (Box 6)
      - 1962 July-1964 June, 1 volume (Box 6)
      - 1964 July-1966 July, 1 volume (Box 6)
      - 1966 August-1970 June, 1 volume (Box 6)
      - 1970 July-1976 June, 1 volume (Box 6)
      - 1976 July-1980 June, 1 volume (Box 6)
    - Connecticut Board of Examiners of Hypertrichologists minutes, 1976 December-1981 January; 1 volume (Box 6)
    - Connecticut Board of Audiologists and Speech Pathologists minutes, 1973-1979 (Box 6)
      - 1973 September-1974 December, 1 volume (Box 6)
      - 1977 March-1979 March, 1 volume (Box 6)
    - Connecticut State Board of Nursing Home Administrators minutes, 1974 October-1979 November; 1 volume (Box 6)
    - Connecticut State Board of Chiropractic Examiners minutes, 1928-1972 (Box 7)
      - 1928 October-1933 November, 1 volume (Box 7)
      - 1939 October-1956 January, 1 volume (Box 7)
      - 1956 April-1972 May, 1 volume (Box 7)
    - Connecticut Board of Examiners of Podiatry minutes, 1930-1979 (Box 7)
      - 1930 June-1969 November, 1 volume (Box 7)
      - 1971 March-1979 June, 1 volume (Box 7)
    - Connecticut Medical Examining Board minutes, 1894-1987 (Box 8)
      - 1894 January-1900, 1 volume (Box 8)
      - 1911 July-1928 December, 1 volume (Box 8)
      - 1929-1939, 1 volume (Box 8)
      - 1975 February-1979 November, 1 volume (Box 8)
      - 1980 January-1987 October, 1 volume (Box 8)
  - 2008-039, 1 cubic foot
    - Board of Examiners for Nursing minutes, 1993-2007 (Box 1)
      See also Accessions 1994-020 and 2011-131.
      - 1993 January 7 - 1995 June 14, 1 volume (Box 1)
      - 1995 June 28 - 1997 June 18, 1 volume (Box 1)
      - 1997 July 9 - 1999 August 18, 1 volume (Box 1)
      - 1999 November 1 - 2001 October 17, 1 volume (Box 1)
      - 2001 November 7 - 2007 December 19, 8 folders (Box 1)
  - 2011-131, .5 cubic feet
    - Board of Examiners for Nursing minutes, 2008-2014 (Box 1)
      See also Accessions 1994-020 and 2008-039.
      Future accruals will be added to this accession.
  - 2014-032, .25 cubic feet
    - Connecticut Stem Cell Research Advisory Committee minutes, 2008-2012 (Box 1)
- Series 36. Commission on the Care and Treatment of the Chronically Ill, Aged and Infirm, 1946; 2002-018; 1 folder
  - Report to the General Assembly, 1946 (Box Shared box)
- Series 37. Division of Health Systems Regulation, 1948-1976; 2004-005; 3.5 cubic feet
  - Nurse Inspectors' Scrapbooks, 1948-1976
    - 1948-1957 (Box 1)
    - 1961-1963 (Box 2)
    - 1963-1937 (Box 3)
    - 1962-1974 (Box 3)
    - 1964-1976 (Box Item 1)
- Series 38. Photographs, 1977-1980; 1994-009; 3 cubic feet
  - (Box 1-3)
- Series 39. Printed Material, 1941-1988; .5 cubic feet
  - Reports, 1957-1988; 1995-072; .5 cubic feet
    - Five-year plan for chronic illness and health of the aging activities in Connecticut, 1964 (Box Shared box)
    - Guidelines for social work departments in short term general hospitals, 1976 January
    - Public Health Social Work Section material, 1988
    - Public Health Social Work Section document draft material, 1988
    - Hiscock health survey, 1957
  - Contributions from the Anna M.R. Lauder Department of Public Health, Yale University, Volume XXI, 1949-1951; 1 volume; 1999-136 (Box Item)
    Received from Ira Hiscock.
  - MacNish, Roslyn Lenore. Cancer Mortality in Connecticut, 1920-1939, 1941; 1 volume; 2002-079 (Box Item)
    Thesis for Master of Public Health, Yale University.
  - Newspaper clippings, 1902-1909; 2006-042 (Box Shared box)
- Series 40. Bureau of Administrative and Support Services, 1995-2002
  - Bureau Chief Elise Gaulin-Kremer files, 1995-2002
    - Quality of Work Life project files, 1996-2001
      This was a joint project between the Dept. of Public Health and the New England Health Care Employees Union, District 1199.
      - Applications, memorandums of understanding, budgets, 1996-2001 (Box 1)
      - Reports from teams, 1997-2001 (Box 1)
      - Materials developed for Quality of Work Life, 2000-2002, undated (Box 1)
      - Training, 2000-2001, undated (Box 1)
      - Meeting agendas and minutes, 1999-2001 (Box 1)
    - Toxicology Laboratory transfer to Dept. of Public Safety, 1995-1999
      - Transfer documents, 1998-1998 (Box 2)
      - Correspondence and status reports, 1996-1999 (Box 2)
      - Procedures review, 1996-1998, undated (Box 2)
      - Interagency Task Force, 1995-1996 (Box 2)